Alice Zhang

User Experience Designer with 7 years of experience in SaaS for B2B environments specializing in visual design, accessibility, and UX strategy. Focusing on transforming ambiguity into clear, user-centred solutions, with a focus on creating memorable experiences.

EXPERIENCE

UI and UX Designer - Pelesys for CAE

Richmond, Canada | January 2022-September 2024

- Designed Figma and Sketch mockups for the Learning Management System app redesign, collaborating with an international team of developers and product managers.
- Improved existing design of the fill-in-the-blanks question type, enhancing the exam creation process for course admins.
- Collaborated with CAE design team to create icon designs for a new design system used in all app rewrites.

UX Designer - Evident Point Software for PressReader

Richmond, Canada | January 2019-November 2021

- Established project foundation for a 500K online school workbook initiative at PressReader's EdTech department; project green-lit after stakeholder presentation.
- Led competitive analysis of 14 products in user research, identifying improvement areas and presenting findings to stakeholders to inform product design.
- Updated client visual branding and print design, adjusting brand colors to meet WCAG AA contrast standards.

UX Designer & Developer - Plaid Consulting

Vancouver, Canada | May 2018-July 2019

- Designed a web app prototype in Adobe XD and Proto.io, incorporating brand colors and typography; built with ReactJS, Bootstrap, SASS, NodeJS, and tracked with Git Bash.
- Conducted user research through interviews with data analysts and institutional researchers to define user needs for the web app.

Web Communications Assistant - DFO Canada

Vancouver, Canada | September 2015-April 2016

- Updated DFO government webpages to a new, accessible HTML/CSS and Bootstrap template.
- Designed monthly newsletters in Photoshop and InDesign.

EDUCATION

Simon Fraser University, Canada

BSc in Interactive Arts and Technology | 2020 Certificate in Computing Studies | 2020

Malmö University, Sweden

Interaction Design BA Course in Full-time Exchange Program | 2017

- alice-zhang-portfolio.com
- alzh13579@gmail.com
- +1 778 788 3568
- in linkedin.com/in/alice-zhang
- alice_slicez
- alice_slicez

DESIGN SKILLS

Wireframing

User Interface Design

Visual Design

Print Design

UX METHODS

User Experience Research

User Interviewing

Competitor Product Analysis

User Journey Mapping

Persona Creation

Usability Testing

Accessibility Testing

TOOLS

Figma

Sketch

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator,

InDesign, Lightroom

Miro, LucidChart

Notion

Airtable

CODING

HTML

CSS/SASS

Javascript

Git Bash

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCIES

English

Mandarin Chinese